A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, Officers' Diaries xFA118
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Weaver, Warren
  - 1933 (Box 501)
    Biology -- Research; Austria; Croatia; Hungary; Zoology; Chemistry; United States; Education; Physics; Germany; Latvia; Czechoslovakia; Poland; Lithuania; Sweden; Estonia; Norway; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Natural Sciences; Weaver, Warren
  - 1934 (Box 501, Reel M Wea 1, Frame 2)
    The focus of grant aid shifts from astronomy and meteorology to natural sciences. Weaver tours various universities to assess experimental biology interests and other Rockefeller Foundation Division of Natural Sciences program interests.
    Biology -- Research; Medicine; Physiology; Sex; Interpersonal relations; Weaver, Warren; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Natural Sciences
  - 1935-1936 (Box 501, Reel M Wea 1, Frame 3)
    In 1935, the present Natural Sciences program of the Rockefeller Foundation is to assist in research related to understanding somatic behavior and aid is given to projects in experimental biology. Weaver interviews professionals in the field of natural sciences and tours universities and research facilities to assess Rockefeller Foundation programs in experimental biology. He tours Cambridge for new natural science research programs. The diary includes an itinerary for a European trip 1-27 May 1935.
    In 1936, The Rockefeller Foundation Natural Sciences program supports research in endocrinology, genetics and physiology to understand human behavior. The diary also documents fellowships.
    Holland (Netherlands: Province); Plant hormones; Geophysics; Denmark; Biology -- Research; Agriculture; Germany; Biophysics; Botany; Genetics; Sex; Immunogenetics; Ireland; England; United States; Sweden; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Natural Sciences; Weaver, Warren; Bergmann, M. (Max)
  - 1937 (Box 502, Reel M Wea 1, Frame 4)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. Weaver discusses research interests and program issues with various professionals in the field of natural sciences. He tours American universities on behalf of the Rockefeller Foundation to assess experimental biology programs, interests and state of natural science education.
    Agriculture; Biology -- Research; Physics; Chemistry; Chemistry, Organic; United States; Weaver, Warren; Bohr, Niels, 1885-1962; Mason, Max; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Natural Sciences
  - 1938 (Box M Wea 2, Folder 5, Box 502)
    The focus of the Rockefeller Foundation Division of Natural Sciences is experimental biology. Aid is given to explore fundamental nature of various natural science fields. The diary also documents Weaver's trip to Europe and includes an itinerary 14-25 January 1938.
    Biology -- Research; Switzerland; Physiology; Zoology; Endocrinology; Nutrition; Genetics; Embryology; Chemistry; United States; Physics; Denmark; France; Germany; Sweden; Weaver, Warren; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Natural Sciences
  - 1939-1940 (Reel M Wea 1, Frame 6, Box 502)
    The 1939 diary documents the Natural Sciences Divison's focus on experimental biology. Weaver interviews various professionals in the field of natural sciences regarding program interests and future research pursuits.
    The 1940 diary documents the Natural Sciences Divison's focus on experimental biology and effects of World War II on Rockefeller Foundation programs.
    Nutrition; Chemistry; Endocrinology; Physics; Biology -- Research; United States; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Natural Sciences; Weaver, Warren; Bohr, Niels, 1885-1962; Mason, Max
  - 1941-1946 (Box 502, Reel M Wea 1, Frame 7)
    The Rockefeller Foundation Division of Natural Sciences focuses on experimental biology and adapting to the needs of World War II. The diary documents artifact production of antibodies, a trip to Mexico to tour the Rockefeller Foundation Mexican Agricultural Program and includes a program for "6th International congress for Applied Mechanics."
    Applied mathematics; Physics; World War II; Biology -- Research; Penicillin; Immunology; Mexico; England; Agriculture; Chemistry; Bohr, Niels, 1885-1962; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Natural Sciences; Weaver, Warren
  - 1947-1948 (Reel M Wea 1, Frame 8, Box 502-503)
    The 1947 diary documents the Rockefeller Foundation's focus of experimental biology to expand knowledge of proteins, enzymes, hormones, steroids and genetics. Weaver interviews professionals in the field of natural sciences and travels to Mexico and South America to survey agricultural programs.
    The 1948 diary documents interests in experimental biology, development of agricultural programs, assistance of European research and results of rebuilding after World War II.
    England; Cytology; Enzymes; Proteins; Genetics; Biophysics; Agriculture; Biology -- Research; Penicillin; Colombia; Venezuela; Guatemala; Brazil; United States; Mexico; France; Nutrition; Denmark; Netherlands; Norway; Sweden; Weaver, Warren; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Natural Sciences
  - 1949 (Reel M Wea 1, Frame 9, Box 503)
    The diary documents Rockefeller Foundation's focus on experimental biology and Weaver's tour of Mexico and South America to survey agricultural programs.
    Zoology; Cytology; Botany; Agriculture; Radiation; Biology -- Research; Uruguay; Argentina; Chile; Peru; Colombia; Mexico; United States; Nutrition; Weaver, Warren; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Natural Sciences
  - 1950 (Reel M Wea 1, Frame 10, Box 503)
    This diary emphasizes the Division of Natural Sciences focus on life sciences and on projects that increase ma's understanding of himself. Weaver also tours Europe and the agricultural programs in Mexico and South America.
    Zoology; Agriculture; United States; Proteins; Corn; Botany; Astronomy; Biology -- Research; Genetics; Chemistry; Physics; France; Switzerland; Mexico; Colombia; England; Scotland; Ireland; Belgium; Weaver, Warren; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Natural Sciences
  - 1951 (Reel M Wea 1, Frame 11, Box 503)
    The Division of Natural Sciences has reorganized into the Division of Natural Sciences and Agriculture. Weaver interviews various professionals in the field of natural sciences and agriculture. He also visits the Colombian Agricultural Program.
    United States; Agriculture; Physics; Colombia; Biology -- Research; Chemistry; Rockefeller Foundation. Natural Sciences and Agriculture; Weaver, Warren
  - 1952 (Box 504, Reel M Wea 3, Frame 12)
    The 1952 diary documents agricultural projects.
    Proteins; Chemistry; Physics; Agriculture; Botany; India; Biology -- Research; Pakistan; Turkey; United States; Mexico; Weaver, Warren; Rockefeller Foundation. Natural Sciences and Agriculture
  - 1953 (Box 504, Reel M Wea 4, Frame 13)
    The focus of the 1953 diary is experimental biology and agriculture.
    United States; Chemistry; Biology -- Research; Agriculture; India; Burma; Thailand; Philippines; Japan; Weaver, Warren; Rockefeller Foundation. Natural Sciences and Agriculture
  - 1954 (Reel M Wea 4, Frame 14, Box 504)
    Weaver takes a trip to Europe to tour universities and observe research facilities. Interviews regarding genetic research are documented.
    DNA; Zoology; Life sciences; Physics; Biology -- Research; Chemistry; Agriculture; Genetics; Sweden; Denmark; England; United States; Karolinska Institutet; Rockefeller Foundation. Natural and Medical Sciences; Weaver, Warren
  - 1955 (Box 504, Reel M Wea 4, Frame 15)
    The diary is arranged by interview and visit. Weaver holds discussions with professionals in the fields of natural and agricultural sciences. He takes a trip to East Asia to survey agriculture programs and maize projects.
    United States; Insecticides; Indonesia; Mexico; India; Cyprus; Thailand; Japan; Agriculture; Biology -- Research; Israel; France; Corn; Plant breeding; Rockefeller Foundation. Natural and Medical Sciences; Weaver, Warren; Rockefeller Foundation. Natural Sciences and Agriculture
  - 1956 (Box 505, Reel M Wea 4, Frame 16)
    The 1956 diary documents Weaver's tour of Africa.
    Ghana; Africa; Nigeria; South Africa; Malaria; Genetics; Agriculture; Biology -- Research; Nutrition; United States; Uganda; Kenya; England; Congo; Rockefeller Foundation. Natural and Medical Sciences; Weaver, Warren
  - 1957 (Box 505, Reel M Wea 5, Frame 17)
    The 1957 diary documents Weaver's trip to Poland.
    Poland; Puerto Rico; Biology -- Research; Agriculture; United States; Weaver, Warren; Rockefeller Foundation. Natural and Medical Sciences
  - 1958 (Box 505, Reel M Wea 5, Frame 18)
    Weaver tours poland to survey life sciences education.
    Biology -- Research; Poland; United States; Agriculture; Genetics; Education; Rockefeller Foundation. Natural and Medical Sciences; Weaver, Warren
  - 1959 (Reel M Wea 5, Frame 19, Box 505)
    This brief diary documents Weaver's last year at the Rockefeller Foundation. it is arranged by interview and visit. He holds conversations with various professionals in the fields of natural and medical sciences.
    Biology -- Research; Medicine; Rockefeller Foundation. Natural and Medical Sciences; Weaver, Warren
- Weir, John M.
  - 1939-1940 (Box 506)
  - 1947 (Box 506)
  - 1948 (Box 506)
  - 1949 (Box 506)
  - 1950 (Box 506)
  - 1940-1942 (Box 506)
  - 1947 (Box 506)
  - 1948 (Box 506)
  - 1949 (Box 506)
  - 1950 (Box 506)
  - Index (Box 506)
  - 1951 (Box 507)
  - 1951-1953 (Box 507)
  - 1952 January-July (Box 507)
  - 1953 (Box 507)
  - 1954 (Box 507)
  - 1955 January-April (Box 507)
  - 1955 May-August (Box 507)
  - 1955 September-December (Box 508)
  - 1956 January-May (Box 508)
  - 1956 June-July (Box 508)
  - 1956 August-December (Box 508)
  - 1957 January-March (Box 508)
  - 1957 April-July (Box 508)
  - 1957 August-December (Box 508)
  - 1958 January-April (Box 508)
  - 1958 May-October (Box 509)
  - Africa, 1958 November-December (Box 509)
  - Africa, 1958-1959 (Box 509)
  - 1959 January-March (Box 509)
  - 1959 April-June (Box 509)
  - 1959 July-December (Box 509)
  - 1960 January-April (Box 510)
  - 1960 May-July (Box 510)
  - 1960 August-December (Box 510)
  - 1961 January-April (Box 510)
  - 1961 May-July (Box 510)
  - 1961 August-December (Box 510)
  - 1962 January-April (Box 511)
  - 1962 May-December (Box 511)
  - 1963 (Box 511)
  - 1964 (Box 511)
  - 1965 (Box 511)
  - 1966 (Box 512)
  - 1967 (Box 512)
  - 1968 January-May (Box 512)
  - 1968 June-December (Box 512)
  - 1969 January-May (Box 512)
  - 1969 June-December (Box 512)
  - 1970 (Box 512)
  - 1971 January-March (Box 512)
  - 1971 April-December (Box 512)
  - 1972 January-April (Box 512)
  - 1972 April-November (Box 512)
  - Index, 1954-1959 (Box 512)
  - Index, 1960-1969 (Box 512)
- Wellhausen, Edwin J.
  - 1952 (Box 513)
  - 1953 (Box 513)
  - 1954 (Box 513)
  - 1955-1956 (Box 513)
  - 1957 (Box 513)
  - 1958 (Box 513)
  - 1959 (Box 513)
  - 1960-1962 (Box 514)
  - 1963-1964 (Box 514)
  - 1965-1966 (Box 514)
  - 1967-1968 (Box 514)
- Wells, Clifford W.
  - 1939, 1941, 1944-1946 (Box 514)
  - 1947-1949 (Box 515)
- Wernimont, Kenneth W.
  - 1952 (Box 515)
  - 1953 January-August (Box 515)
  - 1953 September-December (Box 515)
  - 1954 January-June (Box 515)
  - 1954 July-December (Box 515)
  - 1955 January-May (Box 516)
  - 1955 June-December (Box 516)
  - 1956 January-July (Box 516)
  - 1956 August-December (Box 516)
  - 1957 January-June (Box 516)
  - 1957 July-September (Box 516)
  - 1957 October-December (Box 516)
  - 1958 January-April (Box 517)
  - 1958 May-August (Box 517)
  - 1958 September-December (Box 517)
  - 1959 January-July (Box 517)
  - 1959 August-September (Box 517)
  - 1959 October-December (Box 517)
  - 1960 January-May (Box 518)
  - 1960 June-August (Box 518)
  - 1960 September-December (Box 518)
  - 1961 January-March (Box 518)
  - 1961 April-July (Box 518)
  - 1961 August-December (Box 518)
  - 1962 Diary (with Index) (Box 518)
  - 1963 (Box 519)
  - 1964 (Box 519)
  - 1965 (Box 519)
  - 1966 (Box 519)
  - 1967 (Box 519)
  - 1968 January-June (Box 519)
  - 1968 July-December Diary (with Index) (Box 519)
  - 1969 January-June (Box 519)
  - 1969 July-December Diary (with Index) (Box 519)
  - 1970 (Box 519)
  - 1971-1972 Diary (with Index) (Box 520)
    See also- Ellsworth T. Neumann, 1973-1976.
  - 1973-1974 Diary (with Index) (Box 520)
- West, Robert L.
  - 1962 January (Box 520)
  - 1962 February (Box 520)
  - 1962 March-April (Box 520)
  - 1962 May-July (Box 520)
  - 1962 August-December (Box 520)
  - 1964 May-December (Box 521)
  - 1964 November (Box 521)
  - 1965 January-August (Box 521)
  - 1965 September-December (Box 521)
  - Interviews, 1965 March-April (Box 521)
  - 1966 January-February (Box 521)
- Williams, Bruce E.
  - 1972-1975 (Box 522)
  - 1976-1986 (Box 522)
- Willits, Joseph H.
  - 1939-1941, 132 pages (Box 523, Reel M Wil 1, Frame 1)
    Organized according to interview, this diary spans two years of Willits time spent as Director of Social Sciences of the Rockefeller Foundation. The interviews are with various professionals in the field and the topics of conversation include discussions of various projects, grant proposals and fellowships that RF may contribute resources towards. Some of the topics discussed in the journal include implications of war funding, unemployment, labor studies, urban decay, agricultural science, impact of technology and public administration.
    Diaries; United States; World War II; Labor; Social sciences; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Social Sciences; Willits, Joseph Henry
  - 1944-1946 (Box 523, Reel M Wil 1, Frame 107)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Willits goes to the Southern United States to survey various southern schools. He interviews members of the college faculty and determines which departments are the strongest. The schools surveyed include University of Virginia, University of North Carolina, Duke University, North Carolina State College and North Carolina College for Negroes. Topics covered in this diary include rural poverty, black studies, populations, and World War II. Included in the diary are copies of "Subject Index to Joseph H. Willits ' Dixie Diary", "Racial Relationships in North Carolina", "Farm Labor Shortages and Maximum Production", "Agricultural Interests of Nonfarm Rural Leaders", "Twenty Years of Migration From Farms" and "Rural Industrialization Creates New Problems"
    United States; African Americans; Rural population; Agriculture; World War II; Willits, Joseph Henry; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Social Sciences
  - 1950 (Box 523, Reel M Wil 1, Frame 332)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Willits communicates with various professionals in the field and discusses rebuilding Germany and education during his travels to Germany and Switzerland. Various grant fellowship proposals and surveys are also discussed.
    Education; Germany; Switzerland; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Social Sciences; Willits, Joseph Henry
  - 1951 January-May (Box 523, Reel M Wil 1, Frame 374)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Willits talks to various professionals in the field and discusses projects, grant proposals and fellowships. The Social Science Program is focused on the developing social behavior as a science, applying social science to human problems, developing professionals and establishing a firm basis for social philosophy. Topics in this journal include political behavior, economics and economic history, and international relations. Princeton University's Institute of International Studies is discussed. Willits visits University of Pennsylvania to survey their social science department and attends a conference on Quantitative Description of Technological Change.
    Anthropology; Population; International relations; Political science; Economics; History; Psychology; United States; Sociology; Statistics; Willits, Joseph Henry; Social Science Research Council; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Social Sciences
  - 1951 June-December (Reel M Wil 1, Frame 529, Box 523)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Willits talks to various professionals in the field and discusses projects, grant proposals and fellowships. The Social Science Program is focused on the developing social behavior as a science, applying social science to human problems, developing professionals and establishing a firm basis for social philosophy. Topics in this journal include political behavior, economics and economic history, and international relations. Willits surveys British universities social sciences programs.
    England; United States; Scotland; Sociology; Political science; International relations; Anthropology; Economics; DeVinney, Leland C.; Grant, John B.; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Social Sciences
  - 1952 January-June (Reel M Wil 1, Frame 678, Box 523)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Willits talks to various professionals in the field and discusses projects, grant proposals and fellowships. The Social Science Program is focused on the developing social behavior as a science, applying social science to human problems, developing professionals and establishing a firm basis for social philosophy. Topics in this diary include functioning and management of the economy, human behavior, international relations, and moral and social philosophy.
    Philosophy and religion; United States; International relations; Law; Economics; Political science; Social sciences; Anthropology; Willits, Joseph Henry; Social Science Research Council; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Social Sciences
  - 1952 July-December (Reel M Wil 1, Frame 800, Box 523)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Willits talks to various professionals in the field and discusses projects, grant proposals and fellowships. The Social Science Program is focused on the developing social behavior as a science, applying social science to human problems, developing professionals and establishing a firm basis for social philosophy. Topics in this diary include functioning and management of the economy, human behavior, international relations, and moral and social philosophy. Willits visits University of Basle to survey their RF funded Monetary and Credit Economics research.
    United States; Anthropology; Economics; Switzerland; Social sciences; Law; Philosophy and religion; Political science; International relations; Willits, Joseph Henry; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Social Sciences
  - 1953 January-June (Reel M Wil 1, Frame 916, Box 523)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Willits talks to various professionals in the field and discusses projects, grant proposals and fellowships. The Social Science Program is focused on the developing social behavior as a science, applying social science to human problems, developing professionals and establishing a firm basis for social philosophy. Topics in this diary include functioning and management of the economy, human behavior, international relations, and moral and social philosophy. The area studies program of the Royal Institute of International Affairs and the Law School at University of Wisconsin are featured in this diary.
    Philosophy and religion; Law; International relations; Political science; Human behavior; Methodology; Anthropology; Economics; United States; Social sciences; Willits, Joseph Henry; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Social Sciences; Social Science Research Council
  - 1953 July-December (Box 524, Reel M Wil 1, Frame 1,091)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Willits talks to various professionals in the field and discusses projects, grant proposals and fellowships. The Social Science Program is focused on the developing social behavior as a science, applying social science to human problems, developing professionals and establishing a firm basis for social philosophy. Topics in this diary include functioning and management of the economy, human behavior, international relations, and moral and social philosophy. A study of the resources of South Africa is discussed, the Food Research Institute of Stanford University is surveyed and a trip to Berkeley, California is taken.
    Social sciences; United States; International relations; Political science; Economics; Anthropology; Human behavior; Methodology; Philosophy and religion; Law; Willits, Joseph Henry; Social Science Research Council; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Social Sciences
- Wilson, David B.
  - 1932 January-May (Box 525)
  - 1932 June-December (Box 525)
  - 1934 (Box 525)
  - 1937-1938 (Box 525)
  - 1939-1941 (Box 526)
  - 1940, 1944, 1948, 1950-1951 (Box 526)
- Winegar, Elizabeth A.
  - 1961-1962 (Box 526)
  - 1963 (Box 526)
- Wing, Wilson Mumford
  - 1947-1948 (Box 526)
- Wood, Peter H.
  - 1971-1972 (Box 527)
  - 1973-1974 (Box 527)
- Work, Telford Hindley
  - 1953-1956 (Box 527)
- Worth, C. Brooke
  - 1947-1953 (Box 527)
- Wortman, L. Sterling
  - 1966 January-May (Box 528)
  - 1966 June-December (Box 528)
  - 1967 (Box 528)
  - 1968 (Box 529)
  - 1969 (Box 529)
  - 1970 (Box 530)
  - 1971 (Box 530)
  - 1972 (Box 530)
  - 1973 (Box 531)
  - 1974 (Box 531)
  - 1975 (Box 531)
  - Index, 1966-1974 (Box 531)
- Wray, Joe D.
  - 1961 (Box 532)
  - 1962 (Box 532)
  - 1963 (Box 532)
  - 1964 (Box 532)
  - 1965-1968, 1971, 1973 (Box 532)
- Wright, Bill C.
  - 1968-1969 (Box 533)
- Wright, Christopher
  - 1972-1973 (Box 533)
- Young, Geoffrey Winthrop
  - 1929-1930 (Box 533)
- Yudelman, Montague
  - 1956 (Box 533)
  - 1957 (Box 534)
  - 1958 (Box 534)
  - 1959 (Box 535)
- Zinn, Earl F.
  - 1926-1927 (Box 535)